Guide to the Records of Graham Windham 1804-2011 MS 2916
New-York Historical Society
- Series III - Graham Windham, 1970-2011 (bulk 1977-2010), 11430
  - Subseries III.9 - Office of Development - Photographic Materials, circa 1978-2010, 11984
    - Rwanda Car Wash Benefit, 1994; 51376 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 24)
    - Alumni and Staff at Campus, 1996; 51377 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 25)
    - Annual Meeting, 1997; 51378 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 26)
    - Foster Parent Recognition, 1997; 51379 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 27)
    - Contact sheet location?, 1997; 51380 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 28)
    - Christmas Celebration, undated; 51381 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 29)
    - Bronxville Friends, Family of New York with Matilda Cuomo, undated; 51382 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 30)
    - Ainslie Cottage Dedication, 1994; 51383 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 1)
    - Alvin Ailey Dance School, 1994; 51384 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 2)
    - Essence Magazine and Johnson and Johnson Fantasy Story Hour, 1994; 51385 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 3)
    - Holiday Party at Campus, 1994; 51386 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 4)
    - Julie Saker and Joel Dubenity - E. Hamilton Scholars on Campus, 1994; 51387 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 5)
    - May Taylor Day at Campus, 1994; 51388 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 6)
    - Harlem Day Care Center, 1994; 51389 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 7)
    - 1994-95 Annual Meeting, 51390 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 8)
    - Consumers Union Volunteer Painting Odell Cottage, 1995; 51391 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 9)
    - Children at Campus, 1995; 51392 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 10)
    - Holiday Celebrations/Campus and Family Child Care, 1995; 51393 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 11)
    - Post Legal Adoption Meeting, 1995; 51394 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 12)
    - Harlem Child Care Center also Picture of Judith Jemison, 1995-1996; 51395 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 13)
    - Foster Parents Recognition Day Contact Sheet, 1996; 51396 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 14)
    - Harlem Child Care Center Contact Sheet Various Activities, 1996; 51397 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 15)
    - Independent Living, 1996; 51398 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 16)
    - Williamsburg Center Halloween, 1996; 51399 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 17)
    - Bronxville Community Service, 1997; 51400 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 18)
    - Harlem Child Care Center Graduation, 1997; 51401 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 19)
    - Remington Boys and Girls Club, 1997; 51402 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 20)
    - Volunteer Recognition Luncheon, 1997; 51403 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 21)
    - Viacom Cleanup Harlem Day Care Center, 1997; 51404 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 22)
    - U.S. Trust Company Contact Sheet - Tour by Children, 1998; 51405 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 23)
    - Activities at Campus, 1999-2000; 51406 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 24)
    - Campus Buildings - Basements, 2000; 51407 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 25)
    - Westchester Volunteers, 2000; 51408 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 26)
    - Various Activities Harlem Day Care Center, 2001; 51409 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 27)
    - Harlem Child Care/Hewitt School Volunteers, 2003; 51410 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 28)
    - Grow With Us - Hewitt School Volunteers, 2003; 51411 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 29)
    - Campus Basketball Benefit, 2003; 51412 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 30)
    - Graham School Trip on the Sloop Clearwater, 2004; 51413 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 31)
    - Harlem Child Care - Ogilvy and Mather Volunteers, 2000-2004; 51414 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 32)
    - Finest Day Care Center - Graduation?, 2000-2004; 51415 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 33)
    - 33 Irving Place Staff, 1993; 51426 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 1)
    - Phyllis Barr, Archivist, 1993; 51427 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 2)
    - Staff, Dr. Cynthia Boakye, Attending Pediatrician, 1992 October; 51428 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 3)
    - Alexandra Bowie, Director, Quality Assurance, 1993; 51429 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 4)
    - Staff, Dr. Jennie Brown, Director Residential Treatment Center, 1991; 51430 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 5)
    - Paul Dunn, Director, Family Community Support Division, 1991; 51431 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 6)
    - Staff, Fatima Goldman, Director, Early Childhood Education, 1991; 51432 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 7)
    - Finest Staff, Monika Graff, undated; 51433 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 8)
    - William Hamer III, V.P., Community Program Services, 1991; 51434 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 9)
    - Staff, Sylvia Isabel, Adoption Recruitment Coordinator, 1991; 51435 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 10)
    - Staff Gloria Jones-Grant, Director of Manhattan Mental Health Center, 1990 May; 51436 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 11)
    - Staff, Joyce Lapenn, President, 1988; 51437 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 12)
    - Staff, Joyce Lapenn, President, and Fatima Goldman, Dir. of Early Childhood Education, 1990 May; 51438 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 13)
    - Joyce Lapenn, Executive Director, President, 1991; 51439 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 14)
    - Carmine Magazino, 1986; 51440 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 15)
    - Staff, Dr. Evelyn Opoku, Director Health Services, 1991 December; 51441 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 16)
    - Staff, Barbara G. Patterson, Director of Nursing, 1992 October; 51442 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 17)
    - Staff, Richard Primason, Director of Therapeutic Services, 1992 September; 51443 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 18)
    - Staff, Albert J. Rodriguez, Director Residential Treatment Center, 1993; 51444 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 19)
    - Anita Sorensen, Director FBH and Adoption Div., 1991; 51445 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 20)
    - Family Day Care - MAPP Training Session, 1992; 51446 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 21)
    - Halloween Party, Staff, 1991; 51447 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 22)
    - Foster Boarding Homes, 1995; 51448 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 23)
    - Volunteers and Misc., 1998; 51449 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 24)
    - Gala, 1998; 51450 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 25)
    - Gala, 1998; 51416 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 1)
    - Gala, 1998 and 2001; 51417 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 2)
    - Gala, 2000; 51418 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 3)
    - Gala, 2001; 51419 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 4)
    - Gala, circa 2001-2002; 51420 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 5)
    - Gala, 2004; 51421 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 6)
    - Board members incl. Michael Golden, Staff Member Frank Spain, CFO Chair Georgia Wall, and author Tom Wolfe, circa 2000-2005; 51422 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 7)
    - Chelsea Piers Gala incl. Michael Golden, Georgia Wall, and Tom Wolfe, circa 2000-2005; 51423 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 8)
    - Gala with photos of Chair Michael Golden and author Tom Wolfe, circa 2000-2005; 51424 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 9)
    - Gala with French Ambassador Jean-David Levitte, 2007; 51425 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 10)
    - Mockup for Greenburgh-Graham Brochure, circa 1984; 51451 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 1)
    - Five Year Report Photographs, circa 1984-1986; 51452 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 2)
    - Pictures of Children/Annual Report, circa 1978-1989; 51453 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 3)
    - Annual Report Photos, 1989; 51454 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 4)
    - Annual Meeting, 1990; 51455 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 5)
    - Annual Report Photos incl. Ted Koppel, 1990; 51456 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 6)
    - Suzanne Bales and Michael Ainslie at Gala, 1990; 51457 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 7)
    - Annual Report Photos, 1991; 51458 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 8)
    - Sandra Trim DaCosta, Board Member, 1991; 51459 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 9)
    - Johnson and Higgins Donation, 1991; 51460 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 10)
    - Banco de Popular Donation, 1991; 51461 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 11)
    - Annual Meeting, 1992; 51462 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 12)
    - Michael Ainslie and Joyce Lapenn on Campus School, 1992; 51463 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 13)
    - Bruce Fowle, Board Member, 1992; 51464 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 14)
    - Marian Taylor, Board Member, 1992; 51465 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 15)
    - Photos of Donors, Chase, Food Co-Op, 1992; 51466 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 16)
    - Michael Golden, Board Member, undated; 51467 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 17)
    - Horace Hord, Board Member, undated; 51468 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 18)
    - Barbara Willis Hearst, undated; 51469 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 19)
    - Diane D. Schlinkert, Board Member, undated; 51470 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 20)
    - Charlotte Ottley, Board Member, undated; 51471 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 21)
    - Suzanne Bales, Board Member, undated; 51472 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 22)
    - Solomon House, circa 1983-1985; 51489 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 1)
    - Negatives - Unidentified Sites - Holiday Times, undated and 1985; 51490 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 2)
    - 1980s? Art Show, undated; 51491 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 3)
    - Crafts Workshop - Brooklyn Junior League for Family Day Care in Brooklyn, 1996; 51492 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 4)
    - Campus Harvest Time, circa 1994; 51493 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 5)
    - Davidson Avenue Dedication, 1998; 51473 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 6)
    - Holiday Staff Party, 2003; 51474 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 7)
    - Bronxville Friends Holiday in Harlem Center, 2004-2005; 51475 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous including Basketball Clinic, circa 1990-2010; 51476 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 9)
    - Holiday Party, undated; 51477 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 10)
    - GW Young Professionals at Beacon Center, undated; 51478 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 11)
    - Halloween at ?, undated; 51479 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 12)
    - Countee Cullen Literary Academy ??, undated; 51480 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 13)
    - Campus?, 1999 and undated; 51481 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 14)
    - Children's Art Classes, undated; 51482 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 15)
    - Drawing of Mother and Child?, undated; 51483 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified Various Sites, undated; 51484 (Offsite-box 103, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs to be Identified, undated; 51485 (Offsite-box 103, Folder 2)
    - Visit to Puerto Rico - 2 Photograph Albums, 1992; 51486 (Offsite-box 104)
    - Visit to Puerto Rico 1992 (1 Photograph Album) and Staff Party 1994 (3 Photograph Albums), 1992-1994; 51487 (Offsite-box 105)
    - Photograph Album: [Staff Party 1994] and Photograph Album: Staff Party 2001, circa 1994-2001; 51488 (Offsite-box 106)
    - Photograph Binder, 1994; 51494 (Volume 219)
    - Photograph Binder, 1994-1995; 51497 (Volume 220)
    - Photograph Binder, 1995; 51498 (Volume 221)
    - Photograph Binder, 1995-1997; 51499 (Volume 222)
  - Subseries III.10 - Artifacts, 1986-2002, 51500
    The subseries consists of a mounted letter from Ronald Reagan, 1 proclamation (formerly framed, now removed from its frame for conservation purposes), 1 accreditation notice mounted as a plaque, and 1 award plaque.
    - Mounted Letter from Ronald Reagan, 1986 March 13; 51501 (Box OS 1, Folder 5)
    - Resolucion del Alcalde, Ciudad de Ponce, Ponce Puerto Rico, 1992 April 16; 51502 (Box OS 1, Folder 5)
    - Middle States Accreditation, mounted on wood, 1992 April 15; 51503 (Box OS 3)
    - Children's Champion Award Plaque, 2002; 51504 (Box OS 3)
- Series IV - The Society for the Relief of Poor Widows with Children circa 1804-1881; the New York Methodist Sunday School Society 1835-1837; and the Tuberculosis Preventorium for Children 1910-1949, circa 1804-1949; 11632
  The series consists of three pages of original minutes from a February 11 1804 meeting of a subcommittee of the Society for the Relief of Poor Widows with Small Children (SRPW), with an additional document from April 1881 glued to it. The SRPW was Isabella Graham's earlier organization, out of which the Orphan Asylum Society (OAS) was founded in 1806 as a separate organization. The 1804 document refers to the decision of some SRPW volunteers to educate the children of the poor widows. The document was later framed in cardboard by an unknown person at the OAS, who presumably also wrote and attached the 1881 document as an introduction to the 1804 document. The deteriorating cardboard was removed at the New-York Historical Society in order to conserve the document. The New-York Historical Society also has among its collections eight volumes of board minutes (1797-1932) from the SRPW. The 3-page document in this series is not duplicated in the SRPW board minutes volumes.
  The series also contains one volume of minutes of The New York Methodist Sunday School Society of the West Circuit from May 28, 1835 (the date of its founding) to October 25, 1837. The second half of the handwritten volume is a ledger recording receipts and cash expenses for a household, farm, and garden, created by an unknown person 1844-1851, and a detailed record of varieties of tulips and other flowers planted 1854-1855. It appears that the minutes book was repurposed as a ledger. The relationship of the creator of the first half of the volume to the creator of the second half of the volume is unknown. The reason this volume is in the Graham Windham collection is also unknown.
  The series also contains one small box containing reports and correspondence from the Tuberculosis Preventorium for Children 1910-1921, and an annual report from that organization from 1949. The annual report also provides a summary of the organization from its founding in 1909 through 1948. The Tuberculosis Preventorium, located in Farmingdale New Jersey, merged into Windham Child Care in 1949.
  These three group of records are arranged in chronological order.
  New York Methodist Sunday School Society
  - Society for the Relief of Poor Widows with Small Children Minutes and Additional Document, 1804 February 11 and 1881 April; 51510 (Offsite-box 107, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of the New York Methodist Sunday School Society of the West Circuit and Ledger by Unknown Creator, 1835-1855; 51511 (Volume 223)
  - Tuberculosis Preventorium Correspondence and Reports, 1910-1914; 51512 (Offsite-box 107, Folder 2)
  - Tuberculosis Preventorium Correspondence, 1914-1915; 51513 (Offsite-box 107, Folder 3)
  - Tuberculosis Preventorium Correspondence, 1915-1916; 51514 (Offsite-box 107, Folder 4)
  - Tuberculosis Preventorium Correspondence and Reports, 1917-1921; 51515 (Offsite-box 107, Folder 5)
  - Tuberculosis Preventorium Annual Report, 1949; 51516 (Offsite-box 107, Folder 6)